{
    "id": "f15f075f3be04bec85ea87c531113400",
    "title": "Comparative and superlative quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He was older .................... I thought.",
            "description": "'Than' is the word used in comparative structures. 'Then' is an adverb indicating time.",
            "answers": [
                "then",
                "than",
                "as",
                "like"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6c29a170641b415c990bf3b5cbb73c65"
        },
        {
            "question": "China is ............................ India.",
            "description": "Adjectives of one or two syllables form their comparative forms by adding -er to the positive.",
            "answers": [
                "bigger then",
                "bigger than",
                "more big than"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "08daccd53ba44ebeaad6581b01047ada"
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie is .................................... of the four girls.",
            "description": "We use the comparative to compare one person or thing with another person or thing. We use the superlative to compare somebody or something with the whole group they/it belong(s) to. ",
            "answers": [
                "the prettier",
                "prettier",
                "the prettiest",
                "prettiest"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "db5fb00526fe4b60ab8bcb24fc15073b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not as ................................... my brother.",
            "description": "We use the structure as...as... to make comparisons using positive adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "successful as",
                "successful so",
                "successful than",
                "more successful than"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "184f7f9fabe74e9d97e7ac23193e91bc"
        },
        {
            "question": "That was the ................................ thing to do.",
            "description": "The article 'the' indicates that a superlative adjective is following.",
            "answers": [
                "stupid",
                "funnier",
                "funny",
                "funniest"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "94cd8a2bde464609a40a1a43d84a7781"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was ...................................... gift I have ever received.",
            "description": "The comparative is used in expressions with than.",
            "answers": [
                "most expensive",
                "the most expensive",
                "the more expensive"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c830e47d78df4840b9f8f67be1e67e20"
        },
        {
            "question": "For .................................. information, please visit our website.",
            "description": "Farther indicates distance. Further means additional.",
            "answers": [
                "further",
                "farther",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5bd62c4396ec45de93a0be00701c9bfd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She owns a ............................. collection of antiques.",
            "description": "The article 'a' indicates that we need a positive adjective here.",
            "answers": [
                "fine",
                "finer",
                "finest"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c6134b9b7d4f47f68175e720bbae393c"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was ............................... than I was expecting.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'than' indicates that we need a comparative adjective here.",
            "answers": [
                "cheap",
                "cheaper",
                "cheapest"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b6c35b0735a24234941ae620b9b4a7ff"
        },
        {
            "question": "They are both good girls, but I think Mary is the .................. of the two.",
            "description": "We do not normally use the superlative when the group includes only two persons or things.",
            "answers": [
                "good",
                "better",
                "best",
                "gooder"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4ac6f098807840e28deb65c75e2f1e4d"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the ................................ kitchen I have ever seen.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "filthy",
                "filthier",
                "most filthy",
                "filthiest"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "1b7c7b94cdd2498fa25f66e09e13a513"
        },
        {
            "question": "The older I get, .......................................",
            "description": "The word order in both clauses should be: the + comparative expression + subject + verb.",
            "answers": [
                "the happy I am",
                "I am the happier",
                "the happier I am",
                "I am happier"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9e6500c9644f466794436afe744d7a69"
        }
    ]
}